

Diego Abal

IT ANALYST - CYBERSECURITY - SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

PROFILE

Practical and decisive IT specialist, with more than fifteen years of experience as a network analyst, database, application programming and web development. Responsible and dedicated, with excellent communication and leadership skills. Total commitment to work in a team and with a constant learning attitude. Passionate about new technologies and solving problems in an agile and efficient way.

CONTACT INFORMATION

- Bahía Blanca Buenos Aires - Argentina
- diego.abal@gmail.com
- <u>+54 291 527 95 05</u>
- linkedin.com/in/diegoabal/

LANGUAGES

- Spanish (native)
- English (advanced)
- Portuguese (basic)

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

- Bash
- JavaScript
- Java
- Python
- PHP

WORK EXPERIENCE

• CYBERSECURITY ANALYST

PROTAKEDOWN PTE. LTD T/A PhishFort (phishfort.com)

August 2022 - Present day

My tasks include analysis of phishing, scam and scam incidents in general, analysis of websites, suspicious code, email headers and documents. Specialized in cryptocurrencies, web3, blockchain and also financial institutions, airlines and large corporations. Communication with hosting providers, registrars and online resource management institutions for the removal of malicious resources.

• SYS ADMIN - MIKROTIK NETWORK ADMIN

DESE TECHNOLOGIES S.A. (desetech.com.ar)

February 2022 - August 2022

My duties include the creation of Bash script for backups of MySql servers, CMTS and OLT equipment Administration of Mikrotik routers, CMTS and OLT routers for internet providers. System management with remote monitoring through Zabbix. Help desk, corporate customer support and troubleshooting.

IT ANALYST

PROFERTIL S.A. (profertil.com.ar)

July 2014 - April 2016

My responsibilities included the implementation of IT solutions (Hardware and Software) Installation of operating systems, and all types of applications. Deploy in batch of equipment images, administration and management of backup servers. Fixed and IP Telephony.

• IT ANALYST - APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT

CODIMAT S.A. (codimat.com.ar)

July 2010 - September 2013

My duties included the attention of internal customers in everything related to office computers, notebooks, printers and telephony. Both in the different warehouses and in all the administrative area. I was also in charge of some internal application development in Visual Basic (application maintenance and creation of new resources) and internal web applications developed in PHP language for the visualization of reports and also communication applications with the different AFIP and ARBA services through APIs..

SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

REMIS UNIVERSITARIO S.R.L (remisuniversitario.com.ar)

2004 - 2012

My tasks included the maintenance and installation of new computer equipment. Outsourcing of special services such as telephony or network. Negotiation with suppliers. Responsible for the maintenance of the satellite tracking system of the vehicle fleet. Both in the base of operations and in the mobiles. Installation and maintenance of Windows Server servers and MS-SQL and MySQL databases..

EDUCATION

• Systems Engineering

UNIVERSIDAD NACIONAL DEL SUR

2002 - 2004

• Computer Technician - Application Development Orientation

ESCUELA DE EDUCACIÓN TÉCNICA N°2, BAHÍA BLANCA, ARGENTINA